if you know anything about me well then
you know that dumbbells are my favorite
piece of equipment to work out with
because of the versatility specifically
the unilateral movements that you can do
with them living fit sent me some of
their dumbbells so you know what time it
is it's time for me to share my
experience with y'all
[Music]
what's up my people it's Jake you know
where I am the barbing garage gym and
guess what I've got another review ready
to go for y'all today this time I've got
some dumbbells from living fit now in
this review I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about these
dumbbells from the price and the
features as well as the pros and the
cons and who should or maybe should not
add these to their home gym but before I
get going I have to let you know we've
reviewed a ton of dumbbells on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go and search bar Bend
best dumbbells and you can find out for
yourself which one takes home that
number one spot
[Music]
foreign
okay so let's talk about what I like
about these dumbbells well first and
foremost I love hexagon shaped dumbbells
I really like doing push-ups with my
dumbbells it puts your wrist in a
natural position and that's made a lot
easier when they do feature this hexagon
shape they're also coated in rubber
which is ideal for at-home usage it's
going to prevent your floors from too
much damage if you drop them as well as
protect the actual dumbbell itself and
any surrounding equipment that you may
have now also I really do like these
ergonomically shaped handles right here
if you don't know what an ergonomic
handle is essentially it's thicker in
the middle than it is on the ends it's
going to really fill your palm up nicely
so that's really good there is a
knurling pattern right here it's meant
to line up with your pinky your index
finger and the middle of your palm just
to help you get a good grip and plus
these are available in individual pairs
or as a full set so the weight ranges
from five pounds up to 100 pounds and
five pound increments so a large
majority of y'all are gonna be able to
find some dumbbells that suit your needs
[Music]
all right now let's talk about a few
cons you could run into with these
dumbbells let's talk about the price
first they're not the most expensive
dumbbells on the market but they're also
not the cheapest these are going to
range around four to five dollars per
pound now you can definitely find some
cheaper ones out there but you can also
find some that are way more expensive so
these fall right in the middle of
everything in the end you know it's not
that bad but if they do fall out of your
budget you know you're gonna need to
find some cheaper ones somewhere out
there
um you know the knurling and the
ergonomic handle might not be ideal for
everybody neither one of those features
are a one size fits all feature so keep
that in mind but if you don't want an
ergonomic handle if you want you know a
fully knurled handle you know there's
other options out there for you to
purchase and let's be honest you know
dumbbells tend to take up a really good
amount of space and if you don't have
that amount of space then
you know this is going to be an issue
for you so if that's the case for you
specifically you might want to consider
some adjustable dumbbells just to make
the most of your space that you have
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money as I
previously mentioned you know these are
available in individual pairs or as a
full set so let's break down those
individual pairs for you really fast you
know once again these are going to be
around four to five dollars per pound
going to vary a little bit as you go up
and wait so this 10 pound pair right
here they're going to cost you about 35
bucks or so before shipping 25s are
going to cost you about 90 bucks or so
before shipping these 50s are going to
cost you about 195 dollars and the
hundreds there's gonna be about 415
bucks okay so in terms of the full sets
you have five different ones that you
can work with so the five to fifty pound
set it's going to cost you about 1100
bucks or so five to 75 pound set it's
gonna be around 2 300 if you want to
skip those lighter dumbbells you
absolutely can you can go for the 55 to
75 pound set it's going to cost you
about 1300 bucks 80 to 100 pound set
it's going to cost you about sixteen
hundred dollars and if you want to go
for the full set five to 100 pounds it's
gonna cost you about thirty six hundred
dollars now also worth mentioning yeah
you can purchase these on the living fit
website you can also get them from
Amazon as well if you would prefer to go
and do that now it's really nice that
you can get the full set of five to 100
pounds you know some companies don't
offer that they'll make you do five to
fifty and then fifty to a hundred so
you'll end up spending more money if you
were to have to order two so it's really
nice you can get all of them at one time
[Applause]
okay so let's talk about the build and
some of the features now with these
dumbbells you know as you can see you
know they do have that hexagon shaped
head I personally love it if you drop
them they're not going to roll all the
way across your room you don't have to
chase after them and this rubber is you
know gonna prevent your floors from too
much damage as well as protect the
actual dumbbell itself any surrounding
equipment that you may have now the
heads are made from cast iron the
handles are made from steel don't let
that alarm you you know these are welded
together and then they have the rubber
coating so it's really durable they're
going to last you a really long time
once again you know that handle is made
from steel it is ergonomically shaped so
it's thicker in the middle than it is on
the ends and you have a knurling pattern
that's going to line up with your pinky
your index finger and the middle of your
palm that way you can get a really solid
grip for your workouts now these 10
pound dumbbells have a handle diameter
of right around 1.3 inches and it's
listed online that that's a uniform form
handle diameter I don't really find that
to be the case you know just gripping
these 50s right now they definitely seam
and they look thicker than these 10
Pounders are now in terms of actually
being able to see your weight you're
using you know it's going to pop out at
you and it's just gonna make it super
easy just grab and go and get straight
to your workout these handles are also
Chrome plated I forgot to mention that
just a second ago it's going to be
really nice it's going to add to the
corrosion resistance you might still
want to clean them every so often but
it's still going to add that protection
and that's really nice as well and once
again you know these are available in
individual pairs or as a full set five
pounds up to 100 pounds and five pound
increments so there's a really solid
chance that most of you watching out
there are gonna have some dumbbells that
you can work out with
all right y'all let's go and do a quick
walk around with these dumbbells I'm
gonna go and snag this 10 pounder right
here so you can see up close once again
you know these do have that hexagon
shaped head that I've been ranting and
raving about I just love I prefer my
dumbbells to have that now the heads are
made of cast iron but they are welded to
this steel handle it's gonna be really
solid they don't wobble on you they're
going to last you a long time now you do
have that ergonomically shaped handle
right here so it's thicker in the middle
than it is on the ends and this knurling
pattern right here it's pretty moderate
it's not going to tear your hands up
it's going to give you a good grip but
so this is designed to line up with your
pinky your index finger and your palm
just like that it's going to give you a
really solid grip while you're working
out and lastly you know you do have some
3D lettering right here for your weight
increments really pops out at you that
way you can see exactly which dumbbells
you're grabbing and get right to it
okay so who should purchase the living
fit dumbbells well if you are in fact
looking for some high quality dumbbells
feature rubber coated heads at a pretty
reasonable price this is a really good
place to start looking in my personal
opinion if you're somebody like myself
you like using dumbbells for different
push-up variations you're going to want
some hexagon shaped dumbbells this is
going to be a really good option as well
for you and since you can in fact
purchase these in individual pairs you
can always add on more and expand to
create that full set that you want for
your home gym
foreign
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase these dumbbells
well if you're really really strong and
you need your dumbbells to be heavier
than 100 pounds well
tough luck you're gonna have to keep
looking because as of right now living
fit does not offer any dumbbells above
100 pounds if you're really tight on
Space obviously dumbbells require a good
amount of space especially if you have
more than one pair so that's the case
for you I would definitely recommend
going to find some adjustable dumbbells
but keep in mind
the max weight on majority of adjustable
dumbbells is right around 50 pounds and
lastly a bit of a personal preference
you know if you aren't crazy about the
ergonomically shaped handle or the
knurling style maybe you want a straight
handle that is fully knurled I would
keep looking there's a lot of options
out there as well for you to purchase
all right well that's all I got for you
today on the living fit dumbbells I
really like these I think they could be
a great addition to your home gym I
really like the hexagon shaped head it's
going to allow me to do my push-up
variations and keep my wrists in a
natural position plus it's nice knowing
that it's going to protect any
surrounding equipment they're also not
going to roll all the way across the
room if you do in fact drop them when
you're maxing out on a bench press for
example keep in mind though these do not
exceed 100 pounds so if you do in fact
need heavier dumbbells you will have to
keep looking thanks for hanging out with
me all I hope this video was really
helpful and I was able to answer every
single question you may have about these
dumbbells as always stay posted for my
next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
these dumbbells just search bar Bend
livingfit dumbbell review and you'll
find everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
[Music]